BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
THE PEOPLE, GROUPS, PLACES, AND INCIDENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE PURELY FICTIONAL
الأشخاص والمجموعات والأماكن والحوادث في هذه الدراما خيالية حقًا
From now on, we will have tea together every day.
من الآن فصاعدًا ، سنتناول الشاي معًا كل يوم.
After your lecture, please come to my chambers.
بعد محاضرتك ، من فضلك تعال إلى غرفتي.
I slipped poison
انزلقت السم
in your tea.
في الشاي الخاص بك.
No king was ever safe from poisoning.
لم يكن أي ملك بمأمن من التسمم.
Until you have grown a tolerance for it,
حتى تتسامح معها ،
you will suffer from stomachaches and fevers.
ستعاني من آلام في المعدة وحمى.
But hide your symptoms.
لكن قم بإخفاء الأعراض.
The pain will be yours to manage.
الألم سيكون عليك أن تديره.
The royal physician cannot know.
لا يستطيع الطبيب الملكي أن يعرف.
It should neither be recorded in the infirmary journal.
لا ينبغي تسجيله في مجلة المستوصف.
Resent me for this, Crown Prince.
استاء من هذا ، ولي العهد.
A mother…
ام…
knowingly giving her son…
إعطاء ابنها عن قصد ...
poison to consume!
تستهلك السم!
Poison!
سم!
You would rather have me…
تفضل أن تكون لي ...
grow a tolerance to poison than see me be poisoned.
تنمو التسامح مع السم من رؤيتي أتسمم.
I will drink it.
سوف أشربه.
So please Mother…
لذا من فضلك أمي ...
Do not cry.
لا تبكي.
BLOODY HEART EPISODE 13
قلب دموي الحلقة 13
Look into Jung Euikyun.
انظر إلى Jung Euikyun.
Yes, my lord.
نعم سيدي.
Do you believe that he took in the monk as a boy?
هل تصدق أنه اتخذ الراهب صبيا؟
Coming between the meritorious subjects
بين الموضوعات الجديرة بالتقدير
is not a scheme able to be conjured by the Queen Dowager
ليس مخططًا يمكن أن تستحضره الملكة الأرملة
nor a monk.
ولا راهب.
Were you the one who controlled the Queen Dowager,
هل كنت أنت من سيطر على الملكة الأرملة؟
Your Majesty?
جلالة الملك؟
I, Ham Changik, Governor of Jeolla Province,
أنا هام تشانغيك محافظ جولا ،
bow before you as summoned.
تنحني أمامك كما استدعيت.
Why did Consort Park
لماذا بارك كونسورت
stay behind at the palace?
البقاء في القصر؟
Was she detained?
هل تم اعتقالها؟
An accusation made by a court maid
اتهام من خادمة المحكمة
has the court ladies of Chaeokdang banned from leaving the palace.
منعت سيدات بلاط تشايوكدانغ من مغادرة القصر.
It must be why Consort Park also chose to stay behind.
يجب أن يكون هذا هو السبب وراء اختيار Consort Park أيضًا للبقاء في الخلف.
Is that all?
هل هذا كل شيء؟
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
Let me see your face.
دعني أرى وجهك.
So this is what you look like.
إذن هذا ما تبدو عليه.
I have wished
لقد تمنيت
to praise you in person.
لأثني عليك شخصيا.
I will remember you.
سأتذكرك.
I am much obliged, Your Majesty.
أنا ممتن جدا ، جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
I worry that you are depleting your energy.
أخشى أنك تستنفد طاقتك.
Please rest.
الرجاء الراحة.
You are dismissed.
انت مطرود.
It is too dangerous to meet Siwol in person.
من الخطر للغاية مقابلة Siwol شخصيًا.
Please do not ask to see him again.
من فضلك لا تطلب رؤيته مرة أخرى.
Kyun.
كيون.
Yes, Your Majesty?
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة؟
Do not…
لاتفعل…
abandon him.
التخلي عنه.
He is my loyal subject and one of my people.
إنه موضوعي المخلص وأحد شعبي.
I refuse to only see him…
أنا أرفض أن أراه فقط ...
as a stone on a Go board.
كحجر على لوحة Go.
Father, I hope I did not make a mistake.
أبي ، أتمنى ألا أخطئ.
His Majesty is not as intimidating as I expected.
جلالة الملك ليس مخيفًا كما توقعت.
Why did you not tell him about Consort Park?
لماذا لم تخبره عن كونسورت بارك؟
You said that the news
قلت أن الأخبار
will do no good while he recovers.
لن يجدي نفعا بينما يتعافى.
I have learned what not to say from being your son.
لقد تعلمت ما لا أقوله من كونك ابنك.
Does the Queen Dowager truly see her as a great threat?
هل تعتبرها الملكة الأرملة حقًا تهديدًا كبيرًا؟
Even I cannot sway her.
حتى أنا لا أستطيع التأثير عليها.
When you were out in disguise,
عندما كنت في التنكر
weren't there those who attacked Consort Park?
ألم يكن هناك من هاجم كونسورت بارك؟
Yes, Lady Cho was behind it.
نعم ، كانت السيدة تشو وراء ذلك.
It was by the Queen Dowager's order.
كان بأمر من الملكة الأرملة.
We must bring Consort Park here.
يجب أن نحضر كونسورت بارك هنا.
I will relay the message.
سوف أنقل الرسالة.
Off I go, then.
أذهب ، إذن.
Siwol.
سيوول.
Are you safe?
هل انت بامان
Do not worry about me, Father.
لا تقلق عليّ يا أبي.
Off I go.
ها أنا ذاهب.
Things are looking bad.
تبدو الأمور سيئة.
I will find you a way out.
سوف أجد لك مخرج.
Doing so will be an admission of guilt.
القيام بذلك سيكون بمثابة اعتراف بالذنب.
It will not matter if you lose your life.
لا يهم إذا فقدت حياتك.
Ttonggeum has been detained.
تم اعتقال Ttonggeum.
How long…
حتى متى…
do you expect her to keep silent?
هل تتوقع منها أن تصمت؟
You will be accused of high treason
سوف تتهم بالخيانة العظمى
should she tell a lie.
يجب أن تكذب.
The Queen Dowager has already
الملكة الأرملة لديها بالفعل
banned your court ladies and maids from leaving the palace.
منعت خادماتك وخادماتك من مغادرة القصر.
If you wait any longer,
إذا انتظرت أكثر ،
you might remain trapped here.
قد تظل محاصرا هنا.
Ttonggeum is still not speaking.
لا يزال Ttonggeum لا يتكلم.
So much for the eunuchs saying that she soon will.
الكثير بالنسبة للخصيان الذين يقولون أنها ستفعل ذلك قريبًا.
What do I do?
ماذا أفعل؟
If this continues, I will be arrested for accusing an innocent.
إذا استمر هذا ، فسوف يتم اعتقالي بتهمة بريء.
You framed Consort Park who outranks you,
لقد قمت بتأطير "كونسورت بارك" الذي يتفوق عليك ،
so the punishment will be severe.
لذلك ستكون العقوبة شديدة.
Father!
أب!
Did the Queen Dowager have you summon me?
هل الملكة الأرملة قد استدعتني؟
You dug yourself in a hole knowing that I would dig you out.
لقد حفرت نفسك في حفرة مع العلم أنني سأخرجك.
After all, what the Queen Dowager covets is military power within the palace.
بعد كل شيء ، ما تشتهيه الملكة الأرملة هو القوة العسكرية داخل القصر.
Do not involve me
لا تشركني
in your frivolous feuds.
في نزاعاتك التافهة.
If Consort Park lives, I will lose my life.
إذا عاشت كونسورت بارك ، فسوف أفقد حياتي.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Father, please do not let me die.
أبي ، من فضلك لا تدعني أموت.
Please!
لو سمحت!
Please save me this once!
الرجاء حفظ لي مرة واحدة!
Father, please save me this once.
أبي ، من فضلك أنقذني مرة واحدة.
-Father… -Open the doors.
-الأب… -افتح الأبواب.
Please do not let me die.
من فضلك لا تدعني أموت.
There are not many options for you, Minister Cho.
لا توجد خيارات كثيرة لك يا وزير تشو.
Either become a traitor along with your daughter,
إما أن تصبح خائنًا مع ابنتك ،
or eliminate Councilor Park and Consort Park.
أو القضاء على Councilor Park و Consort Park.
I do not follow.
أنا لا اتبع.
Who will then manage state affairs
من سيتولى بعد ذلك إدارة شؤون الدولة
while His Majesty remains incapacitated?
بينما جلالة الملك لا يزال عاجزا؟
That is not my concern.
هذا ليس شاغلي.
The Central Army consists of those loyal to Councilor Park.
يتكون الجيش المركزي من أولئك الموالين لـ Councilor Park.
Armed patrol officers within the palace that are only loyal to him
ضباط دورية مسلحون داخل القصر موالون له فقط
must surely make you just as anxious.
يجب أن يجعلك بالتأكيد نفس القلق.
Focus on guarding the palace as you have been.
ركز على حراسة القصر كما كنت.
All I need is Councilor Park and Consort Park to be gone.
كل ما أحتاجه هو أن يرحل كونسورت بارك و كونسورت بارك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty, are you awake?
جلالة الملك ، هل أنت مستيقظ؟
I left her
تركتها
to fend for herself.
لتدافع عن نفسها.
Send word to the Queen Dowager's Palace.
أرسل كلمة إلى قصر الملكة الأرملة.
I can no longer leave Consort Park alone in the palace.
لم يعد بإمكاني ترك حديقة كونسورت وحدي في القصر.
Yes, Your Majesty. I am sure word has been delivered.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.  أنا متأكد من أن الكلمة قد وصلت.
May I ask why you have not ordered the Left State Councilor to resign?
هل لي أن أسأل لماذا لم تأمروا مستشار الدولة اليساري بالاستقالة؟
He has made it clear that he will not accept it.
لقد أوضح أنه لن يقبلها.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو ،
the meritorious subjects have been loyal to him for a long time.
كان الأشخاص الجديرون بالتقدير مخلصين له لفترة طويلة.
If they choose to side with him once again--
إذا اختاروا الوقوف معه مرة أخرى--
Do you hold resentment toward Councilor Park?
هل تشعر بالاستياء تجاه حديقة كونسيلور؟
If not, let this matter rest.
إذا لم يكن الأمر كذلك ، دع هذا الأمر يرتاح.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
When will His Majesty die?
متى يموت جلالة الملك؟
Once he does,
بمجرد أن يفعل ،
the Minister of War will be of no concern.
وزير الحرب لن يكون مصدر قلق.
He will succumb to his illness as is wished by the Maitreya.
سوف يستسلم لمرضه كما تتمنى المايترية.
Stand down.
ينسحب - يتراجع.
Are you afraid of what may come?
هل تخاف مما قد يأتي؟
To have such armed guards beside you.
أن يكون بجانبك حراس مسلحون.
Does that wicked monk advise you to get rid of me?
هل ينصحك هذا الراهب الشرير بالتخلص مني؟
Yes, and so didn't they start turning their backs to you?
نعم ، ولم يبدأوا في إدارة ظهورهم لك؟
What are you planning to do after gaining all that power?
ما الذي تخطط للقيام به بعد اكتساب كل هذه القوة؟
What exactly is power to you?
ما هي القوة بالضبط بالنسبة لك؟
They had the audacity to decline your summons.
لقد كانت لديهم الجرأة لرفض استدعائك.
It is why I must meet them in person.
لهذا السبب يجب أن أقابلهم شخصيًا.
Being in office is what they have been continuously avoiding.
أن يكونوا في المنصب هو ما كانوا يتجنبونه باستمرار.
Stubborn as they are, they will fight till the death for their beliefs.
هم عنيدون ، سيقاتلون حتى الموت من أجل معتقداتهم.
But they are the ones who will replace
لكنهم هم من سيحل محلهم
the current meritorious subjects.
الموضوعات الجديرة بالتقدير الحالية.
They say that the Office of Palace Eunuchs has gone as far
يقولون أن مكتب قصر الخصيان قد ذهب إلى هذا الحد
as to replacing the State Council.
لتحل محل مجلس الدولة.
Why would you want to appear in front of such filth?
لماذا تريد أن تظهر أمام مثل هذا القذارة؟
We only worry that you will lose your life in vain.
نحن نشعر بالقلق فقط من أنك ستفقد حياتك سدى.
Ever since scholar Yoo Haksoo was executed,
منذ أن تم إعدام الباحث يو هاكسو ،
I have stayed clear from state affairs.
لقد بقيت بعيدة عن شؤون الدولة.
I also turned a blind eye while meritorious subjects abused their power.
كما أنني غضت الطرف بينما أساء الأشخاص الجديرون بالتقدير سلطتهم.
However, students of the Confucian Academy have either been executed or imprisoned
ومع ذلك ، فقد تم إعدام طلاب الأكاديمية الكونفوشيوسية أو سجنهم
while speaking their minds
بينما يتحدثون بأفكارهم
and that I cannot stand idly by.
وأنني لا أستطيع أن أقف مكتوفي الأيدي.
Do not stop me from a righteous death.
لا تمنعني من الموت الصالح.
How foolish of you.
يا لك من حماقة.
You clearly do not realize when to be proactive
من الواضح أنك لا تدرك متى تكون استباقيًا
and when to await the right time.
ومتى تنتظر الوقت المناسب.
You refused to answer your King's summons.
لقد رفضت الرد على استدعاء ملكك.
You turned a blind eye to political matters
لقد غضت الطرف عن الأمور السياسية
and buried yourself only in books.
ودفنت نفسك في الكتب فقط.
Your… Your Majesty!
جلالتك ... يا صاحب الجلالة!
Stay safe and prepare for what is to come.
ابق آمنًا واستعد لما هو آت.
Once I remove the traitors within the palace,
بمجرد أن أزيل الخونة من داخل القصر ،
I will appoint members of the Sarim
سأعين أعضاء من ساريم
and have them design the world they have been dreaming of.
وجعلهم يصممون العالم الذي كانوا يحلمون به.
I promise you this…
أعدك بهذا ...
as your King.
ملكك.
I, classics licentiate Moon Simhyun, bow down to His Majesty.
أنا ، المرخصين الكلاسيكيين مون سيمهيون ، أنحني لجلالة الملك.
-We bow down to His Majesty.
- نسجد لجلالة الملك.  - نسجد لجلالة الملك.
Before we join the court,
قبل أن ننضم إلى المحكمة ،
we wish to know where you stand.
نرغب في معرفة مكانك.
Go ahead.
إنطلق.
Do you believe
هل تصدق
that Yoo Haksoo was behind your mother's murder?
أن يو هاكسو كان وراء مقتل والدتك؟
No.
رقم.
Of course I am well aware of how he was unfairly treated.
بالطبع أنا أعي جيدًا كيف عومل بشكل غير عادل.
Then,
ثم،
please accept our appeal regarding his status as a traitor.
الرجاء قبول استئنافنا بخصوص وضعه كخائن.
For a long time, my friend has been wrongfully known as a murderer.
لوقت طويل ، عُرف صديقي ظلماً بالقاتل.
If you reinstate his status,
إذا أعدت وضعه ،
those who support his beliefs
أولئك الذين يؤيدون معتقداته
will choose to be loyal to you.
سيختار أن يكون مخلصًا لك.
I give you my word.
أوعدك.
Someday,
في يوم ما،
I will reinstate Yoo Haksoo's noble status.
سأعيد وضع يو هاكسو النبيل.
My lord, when did you arrive at the office?
يا سيدي متى وصلت إلى المكتب؟
How silly of me to have made you worry.
كم من السخف جعلتك تقلق.
Have you been well?
هل كنت بخير
Yes, Lord Kim. Are you feeling better now?
نعم ، اللورد كيم.  هل تشعر بالتحسن الآن؟
Without you present,
بدون هديتك
it has been a challenge to gather the opinions of the Three Offices.
لقد كان من الصعب جمع آراء المكاتب الثلاثة.
They are many other pressing matters at hand though.
هناك العديد من الأمور الملحة الأخرى في متناول اليد بالرغم من ذلك.
-Sorry? -The Queen Dowager has announced
-آسف؟  - أعلنت الملكة الأرملة
that continued disapproval from the Three Offices
أن استمرار عدم الموافقة من المكاتب الثلاثة
will lead to limitations within
سيؤدي إلى قيود في الداخل
the Office of the Censor General and the Office of Inspector General.
مكتب المراقب العام ومكتب المفتش العام.
She will ban us from remonstrating?
ستمنعنا من الاحتجاج؟
Who is she to announce that?
من هي لتعلن ذلك؟
It is why a joint appeal
هذا هو السبب في النداء المشترك
from the Three Offices shall never be mentioned again.
من المكاتب الثلاثة لن يتم ذكرها مرة أخرى.
If we do not,
ان لم نفعل،
officials of the Three Offices will be forbidden to speak.
سيتم منع مسؤولي المكاتب الثلاثة من الكلام.
Lord Kim, it is why we must speak of this wrongful behavior.
اللورد كيم ، لهذا السبب يجب أن نتحدث عن هذا السلوك غير المشروع.
Are you not aware that even your father is being shunned by the court?
ألا تدرك أنه حتى والدك منبوذ من قبل المحكمة؟
The inspector general and the censor general have agreed.
المفتش العام والمراقب العام اتفقا.
Now, put this matter to rest.
الآن ، تخلص من هذه المسألة.
But Lord Kim…
لكن اللورد كيم ...
Ttonggeum…
تنغيوم
was born in your home.
ولد في منزلك.
You must have grown a soft spot for her.
يجب أن تكون قد نمت لها بقعة ناعمة.
Her being injured
تعرضها للإصابة
will only make you feel terrible.
سيجعلك فقط تشعر بالفزع.
A soft spot for a servant who is worth less than livestock?
بقعة ناعمة لخادم أقل قيمة من البهائم؟
Or maybe that only applies to you.
أو ربما هذا ينطبق عليك فقط.
She only came to work at the palace
لقد جاءت للعمل في القصر فقط
so that she could protect you.
حتى تتمكن من حمايتك.
If you do not wish to see her get hurt,
إذا كنت لا ترغب في رؤيتها تتأذى ،
confess the truth.
اعترف بالحقيقة.
I must see…
لابد ان أرى…
the Queen Dowager.
الملكة الأرملة.
She is at the royal office.
هي في المكتب الملكي.
Maybe you should find her there.
ربما يجب أن تجدها هناك.
Lady Cho,
سيدة تشو ،
you should request Ttonggeum's release.
يجب أن تطلب الإفراج عن Ttonggeum.
I…
أنا…
no longer have a say in the matter.
لم يعد لها رأي في هذه المسألة.
Eunuch Heo will soon bring back the people at Bamboo Grove Village.
سيعيد Eunuch Heo قريبًا الناس في Bamboo Grove Village.
Even without Ttonggeum's words,
حتى بدون كلام Ttonggeum ،
her identity will soon be revealed.
سيتم الكشف عن هويتها قريبا.
-What did I tell you? -Goodness.
-ماذا أخبرتك؟  -صلاح.
-Look! -What on earth?
-نظرة!  -ماذا على الارض؟
What now?
ماذا الان؟
Why are you back here with these men again?
لماذا عدت إلى هنا مع هؤلاء الرجال مرة أخرى؟
-What is it this time? -We have already paid our tributes.
-ما هو هذا الوقت؟  - لقد دفعنا بالفعل تحياتنا.
Why must you scare us again?
لماذا يجب أن تخيفنا مرة أخرى؟
I am just as baffled.
أنا فقط في حيرة من أمري.
The order comes from someone of high rank.
يأتي الترتيب من شخص ذي رتبة عالية.
-What? -How high?
-ماذا او ما؟  -كم ارتفاعه؟
Will we be taken away again?
هل سيتم أخذنا بعيدا مرة أخرى؟
I am just as clueless, so take it up with the village governor.
أنا جاهل تمامًا ، لذا تناول الأمر مع حاكم القرية.
-Take them away. -Yes, my lord.
-خذهم بعيدا.  -نعم سيدي.
-No! -I will not go.
-رقم!  -لن أذهب.
Leave her and take me instead.
اتركها وخذني بدلا من ذلك.
At least tell us why.
على الأقل قل لنا لماذا.
Halt!
وقف!
-But… -Goodness.
-ولكن… -صالح.
What is this about?
عن ماذا يدور الموضوع؟
Step aside!
تنحى!
The Governor of Jeolla Province has spoken.
تحدث محافظ جولا.
The Governor of Jeolla Province?
محافظ جولا؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو ،
you seem to have lost your way.
يبدو أنك فقدت طريقك.
I once saved Ttonggeum when she was discarded with a disease.
لقد أنقذت ذات مرة Ttonggeum عندما أصيبت بمرض.
After recovering, she refused to live as a runaway slave
بعد أن تعافت ، رفضت أن تعيش كعبد هارب
and opted to return to her master.
واختارت العودة إلى سيدها.
I could not stop her.
لم أستطع منعها.
This time, I wish not to regret my choice.
هذه المرة ، لا أود أن أندم على اختياري.
I will speak to the Queen Dowager at the royal office.
سأتحدث إلى الملكة الأرملة في المكتب الملكي.
You cannot.
لا يمكنك.
A lady of the Internal Court must not step inside the royal office.
يجب على سيدة في المحكمة الداخلية ألا تتدخل داخل المكتب الملكي.
Please think only of your own safety now.
من فضلك فكر فقط في سلامتك الآن.
-I cannot. -Your Highness!
-لا استطيع.  -صاحب السمو!
You said Ttonggeum could speak at any moment.
قلت أن Ttonggeum يمكنه التحدث في أي لحظة.
I cannot knowingly let her withstand excruciating pain.
لا يمكنني السماح لها عن قصد بتحمل الألم الرهيب.
Do not follow me. That is an order.
لا تتبعني.  هذا أمر.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو ،
Consort Park has requested an audience at the royal office.
طلبت كونسورت بارك الحضور في المكتب الملكي.
Consort Park wishes to step inside the royal office?
كونسورت بارك ترغب في الدخول إلى المكتب الملكي؟
That is preposterous!
هذا غير معقول!
A lady of the Internal Court in the royal office
سيدة من المحكمة الداخلية في المكتب الملكي
is most taboo amongst taboos!
هو أكثر المحرمات بين المحرمات!
Never in history has there been such an audacious request!
لم يكن هناك مثل هذا الطلب الجريء في التاريخ!
Should I send her away?
هل يجب أن أرسلها بعيدًا؟
Consort Park is smart and is probably aware of the consequences.
Consort Park ذكي وربما يدرك العواقب.
I should hear what she has to say.
يجب أن أسمع ما لديها لتقوله.
Have her enter.
اجعلها تدخل.
I am curious as to how pressing this matter is.
لدي فضول لمعرفة مدى إلحاح هذا الأمر.
Speak.
يتكلم.
By your orders,
بأوامرك ،
one of my court maids was taken by the Office of Palace Eunuchs.
إحدى خادماتي في البلاط تم أخذها من قبل مكتب الخصيان في القصر.
It was only to prove your innocence.
كان فقط لإثبات براءتك.
To which I am grateful.
وأنا ممتن له.
However,
لكن،
it does not fall under the jurisdiction of the Office of Palace Eunuchs.
أنها لا تقع ضمن اختصاص مكتب قصر الخصيان.
This is nothing but a frivolous matter.
هذه ليست سوى مسألة تافهة.
That may be,
قد يكون ذلك ،
but this is a direct violation of the State Tribunal's authority.
لكن هذا انتهاك مباشر لسلطة محكمة الدولة.
You dare intrude on the royal office
أنت تجرؤ على التطفل على المكتب الملكي
just because of a servant?
فقط بسبب خادم؟
Remove her!
أزلها!
We will discuss a rightful punishment for you.
سنناقش العقوبة الصحيحة بالنسبة لك.
I am…
انا…
with child of His Majesty's blood.
مع طفل من دم جلالة الملك.
Your grandchild.
حفيدك.
I am pregnant with His Majesty's child, Your Highness.
أنا حامل بطفل جلالة الملك ، صاحب السمو.
If you sympathize with me in any way,
إذا كنت تتعاطف معي بأي شكل من الأشكال ،
please allow me to join His Majesty
واسمحوا لي أن أنضم إلى جلالة الملك
at the royal villa where he currently recuperates.
في الفيلا الملكية حيث يتعافى حاليا.
There is a possibility of a boy…
هناك احتمال وجود ولد ...
being born.
يولد.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
It is a joyous event for the entire nation.
إنه حدث بهيج للأمة بأسرها.
I am nothing but proud.
أنا لست سوى فخور.
The Central Army consists of those loyal to Councilor Park.
يتكون الجيش المركزي من أولئك الموالين لـ Councilor Park.
Armed patrol officers within the palace that are only loyal to him
ضباط دورية مسلحون داخل القصر موالون له فقط
must surely make you just as anxious.
يجب أن تجعلك بالتأكيد نفس القلق.
Why did the monk have the Queen Dowager
لماذا كان الراهب لديه الملكة الأرملة
take control of the troop dispatch token first?
السيطرة على رمز إرسال القوات أولاً؟
If His Majesty is truly behind it all,
إذا كان جلالة الملك وراء كل ذلك حقًا ،
he would not let her take control of what is needed
لم يسمح لها بالسيطرة على ما هو مطلوب
to summon the troops all across the country.
لاستدعاء القوات في جميع أنحاء البلاد.
The troop dispatch token belongs to the Ministry of War.
رمز إرسال القوات ينتمي إلى وزارة الحرب.
Anyone who wishes to get his hands on it
لمن يريد أن يضع يديه عليها
shall be dealt with by the law.
يتم التعامل معها بموجب القانون.
That is what you once said.
هذا ما قلته ذات مرة.
Yes, and I only wish to see that you still have it.
نعم ، وأتمنى فقط أن أرى أنه لا يزال لديك.
I am currently in charge of the palace security.
أنا حاليًا مسؤول عن أمن القصر.
Do not do anything that will have me doubt you.
لا تفعل أي شيء يجعلني أشك فيك.
I see that you already do.
أرى أنك فعلت ذلك بالفعل.
You are the one
أنت الوحيد
who keeps me in check by controlling the Central Army.
الذي يبقيني تحت السيطرة من خلال السيطرة على الجيش المركزي.
Why is it
لماذا هو
that they report their schedule to you before reporting to the Ministry of War?
أنهم يبلغونك بجدولهم الزمني قبل تقديم تقرير إلى وزارة الحرب؟
From this moment on, those who report to you
من هذه اللحظة فصاعدا ، أولئك الذين يبلغونك
will be met with military discipline.
سيقابل الانضباط العسكري.
Are you siding with the Queen Dowager?
هل تقف مع الملكة الأرملة؟
I…
أنا…
do not side with anyone.
لا تقف مع أي شخص.
Announcing that in these current times
الاعلان عن ذلك في هذه الاوقات الحالية
is the same as saying that you are.
هو نفس القول بأنك كذلك.
Councilor Park.
كونسيلور بارك.
Lord Cho, Consort Park announced that she is with child.
أعلن اللورد تشو ، كونسورت بارك أنها مع طفل.
Congratulations!
تهانينا!
You are truly with child.
أنت حقا مع الطفل.
I am overjoyed.
أشعر بسعادة غامرة.
And I am honored, Your Highness.
ويشرفني سموك.
I should grant you a wish for your tremendous achievement.
أود أن أمنحك أمنية لتحقيق هذا الإنجاز الهائل.
In what way though?
بأي طريقة بالرغم من ذلك؟
Then,
ثم،
please have my court maid released from the Office of Palace Eunuchs.
الرجاء إطلاق سراح خادمتي في المحكمة من مكتب الخصيان في القصر.
To know that she is being tortured following a groundless claim
لتعلم أنها تتعرض للتعذيب بعد ادعاء لا أساس له
has me…
لدي…
uneasy.
غير مستقر.
A lady with child should never be troubled.
لا ينبغي أبدا أن تتضايق سيدة لديها طفل.
I will allow it.
سأسمح بذلك.
Congratulations on your pregnancy.
مبروك على حملك.
However, you should have kept it hidden.
ومع ذلك ، كان يجب أن تبقيها مخفية.
You very well know why.
أنت تعرف جيدًا لماذا.
Why did you choose to reveal it instead?
لماذا اخترت الكشف عنها بدلا من ذلك؟
It was to save
كان من أجل الحفظ
one of my people whom she has been torturing.
أحد أبناء شعبي الذين كانت تعذبهم.
The Central Army will guard Chaeokdang.
سيحرس الجيش المركزي تشايوكدانغ.
You need not worry.
لا داعي للقلق.
Once His Majesty returns to the palace,
بمجرد عودة جلالة الملك إلى القصر ،
this fruitless disruption…
هذا الاضطراب غير المجدي ...
will come to an end.
سوف ينتهي.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
The Office of Palace Eunuchs will bring Ttonggeum out.
سيقوم مكتب قصر الخصيان بإخراج Ttonggeum.
No. Tell them that we will get her ourselves.
لا ، أخبرهم أننا سنحصل عليها بأنفسنا.
-Also have a stretcher ready. -Yes, Your Highness.
-أيضا نقالة جاهزة.  -نعم سموكم.
Have you notified the Royal Medical Office?
هل أبلغت المكتب الطبي الملكي؟
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
She must be severely injured.
يجب أن تكون مصابة بجروح خطيرة.
Step aside!
تنحى!
Has it not occurred to you that harming the pregnant consort
ألم يخطر ببالك إيذاء القرين الحامل
will result in all eunuchs losing their lives?
سوف يؤدي إلى فقدان جميع الخصيان حياتهم؟
No one will dare to block your way.
لن يجرؤ أحد على سد طريقك.
Please enter.
تفضل.
Every one of your actions…
كل واحد من أفعالك ...
will be remembered.
سيذكر.
Please wait out here while I check on her first.
من فضلك انتظر هنا بينما أتحقق منها أولاً.
I advise that you listen to her.
أنصح أن تستمع إليها.
The sight will not be pleasant for the baby.
لن يكون المشهد ممتعًا للطفل.
Not even I have seen a girl as relentless as her.
حتى أنني لم أر فتاة لا هوادة فيها مثلها.
What did you do to her?
ماذا فعلت لها؟
She is alive… for now.
هي على قيد الحياة ... حتى الآن.
Ttonggeum.
تنغيوم.
Miss.
يغيب.
Yes.
نعم.
Miss…
يغيب…
It must have been terrifying.
لا بد أنها كانت مرعبة.
It was.
كانت.
I…
أنا…
was afraid…
كان خائفا…
that I might lose my mind and tell lies.
أنني قد أفقد عقلي وأقول أكاذيب.
You did not say anything.
أنت لم تقل شيئا.
Let us get you out of here.
دعنا نخرجك من هنا
Miss.
يغيب.
Yes?
نعم؟
Can I…
هل استطيع…
now…
حاليا…
get…
احصل على…
some rest?
بعض الراحة؟
Yes.
نعم.
I wish…
أتمنى…
to sleep now.
للنوم الآن.
Miss.
يغيب.
You know,
أنت تعرف،
I do not need to be born as a noble in my next life.
لست بحاجة لأن أكون نبيلة في حياتي القادمة.
Why not?
لما لا؟
Is it not your dream
أليس هذا حلمك
to enjoy all the white rice and meat soup you can possibly have?
للاستمتاع بجميع الأرز الأبيض وشوربة اللحوم التي يمكن أن تتناولها؟
I would not mind being a servant or livestock for that matter
لا أمانع أن أكون خادمًا أو ماشية لهذه المسألة
as long as you are my master.
ما دمت سيدي.
Living in your shadows eating whatever you give me
تعيش في ظلك وتأكل ما تعطيني إياه
will be a satisfying life.
ستكون حياة مرضية.
A happy one too.
سعيد أيضا.
Ttonggeum…
تنغيوم
If Consort Park is carrying a child,
إذا كان Consort Park يحمل طفلاً ،
what would that mean for the Queen Dowager's regency?
ماذا يعني ذلك بالنسبة لوصاية الملكة الأرملة؟
It is impossible to predict what will happen.
من المستحيل التنبؤ بما سيحدث.
Then…
ثم…
what will happen to me, brother?
ماذا سيحدث لي اخي؟
Your family is behind you, Lady Cho.
عائلتك خلفك يا سيدة تشو.
I've been informed of Ttonggeum's death.
لقد تم إبلاغي بوفاة Ttonggeum.
The lowly rat paid for how she humiliated me.
لقد دفعت الجرذ المتواضع ثمن كيف أهانتني.
I am not responsible, am I?
أنا لست مسؤولا ، أليس كذلك؟
Right?
حق؟
I am to step down as regent?
أنا على التنازل عن منصب وصي على العرش؟
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
It is the right course of action…
إنه مسار العمل الصحيح ...
to await the child's birth and then decide on a successor.
انتظار ولادة الطفل ثم اتخاذ قرار بشأن من يخلفه.
Please step down as regent
يرجى التنحي كوصي
and accept the advice of the royal court.
وتقبل مشورة الديوان الملكي.
-Please accept our advice.
-يرجى قبول نصيحتنا.  -يرجى قبول نصيحتنا.
I will keep it in mind.
سأضع الامر في بالي.
You are dismissed.
انت مطرود.
They wish for me to relinquish power to Consort Park.
إنهم يرغبون في أن أتخلى عن السلطة لـ Consort Park.
It seems as though
يبدو كما لو
I must walk the path of the great King Sejo.
يجب أن أسير في طريق الملك العظيم سيجو.
You once told me the Capital was abundant with men who will do anything for a price.
لقد أخبرتني ذات مرة أن العاصمة كانت وفيرة بالرجال الذين سيفعلون أي شيء مقابل ثمن.
Anything and everything, Your Highness.
أي شيء وكل شيء يا صاحب السمو.
Bring them in this instant.
أحضرهم في هذه اللحظة.
Ignore procedure and all justifications.
تجاهل الإجراء وجميع المبررات.
Tonight, Consort Park and those who wish to serve her…
الليلة ، كونسورت بارك وأولئك الذين يرغبون في خدمتها ...
will be murdered.
سيقتل.
It is not like you to be startled this easily.
ليس الأمر مثلك أن تذهل بهذه السهولة.
Well, of course you are on edge.
حسنًا ، بالطبع أنت على حافة الهاوية.
Our fate usually depends on those we serve.
يعتمد مصيرنا عادة على من نخدمهم.
Are you here to offer me a way to live?
هل أنت هنا لتقدم لي طريقة للعيش؟
This is exactly why I am fond of you.
هذا هو بالضبط سبب إعجابي بك.
Once Consort Park dies,
بمجرد وفاة كونسورت بارك ،
you will be given a chance to contribute to the cause.
سوف تحصل على فرصة للمساهمة في القضية.
Consort Park who tried to murder the King
القرين بارك الذي حاول قتل الملك
took her own life in fear of her false pregnancy being revealed.
انتحرت خوفًا من كشف حملها الزائف.
That is all you have to say.
هذا كل ما عليك أن تقوله.
Do not feel bad.
لا تشعر بحزن.
No one acknowledges loyalty anyway.
لا أحد يعترف بالولاء على أي حال.
Never have I seen anyone of rank care for those that serve them,
لم أر أبدًا أي شخص في مرتبة يهتم بمن يخدمونهم ،
so why must we be loyal to them?
فلماذا يجب أن نكون مخلصين لهم؟
That is correct.
هذا صحيح.
No one of rank has ever been that generous.
لم يكن أي شخص في الرتبة بهذا السخاء من قبل.
Can I count on you?
هل يمكنني الاعتماد عليك
Well,
نحن سوف،
the court ladies and maids of Chaeokdang are confined to the palace anyway.
سيدات البلاط والخادمات في تشاوكدانغ محصورات في القصر على أي حال.
When will it happen?
متى سيحدث ذلك؟
Tonight.
الليلة.
You need to eat something.
تحتاج أن تأكل شيئا.
You have been starving all day.
كنت تتضور جوعا طوال اليوم.
The Queen Dowager…
الملكة الأرملة ...
ordered Ttonggeum's body to be discarded.
أمرت جثة Ttonggeum بالتخلص منها.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
Court ladies cannot die within palace walls.
لا يمكن لسيدات البلاط أن يموتن داخل أسوار القصر.
I cannot let this happen.
لا يمكنني ترك هذا يحدث.
She should be properly buried at least.
يجب دفنها بشكل صحيح على الأقل.
Did you do as told?
هل فعلت ما قيل؟
Yes, Court Lady Choi.
نعم ، سيدة المحكمة تشوي.
What…
ماذا او ما…
did you slip in my tea?
هل انزلقت في الشاي الخاص بي؟
do you plan on doing?
هل تخطط لفعل؟
Today's patrol and night duty will only be conducted by the Palace Guard.
سيتم إجراء الدوريات والواجب الليلي اليوم من قبل حرس القصر فقط.
It is the Queen Dowager's orders. Also…
إنها أوامر الملكة الأرملة.  ايضا…
the Central Army's actions will be publicized,
سيتم الإعلان عن أعمال الجيش المركزي ،
and they will be punished.
وسوف يعاقبون.
The Central Army was chased out of the palace
تم طرد الجيش المركزي من القصر
and the Palace Guards were dispatched to manage a forest fire.
وتم إرسال حراس القصر لإدارة حريق الغابة.
The palace is empty.
القصر فارغ.
All that is left
كل ما تبقى
is for you to fill out the kill list.
هو أن تملأ قائمة القتل.
Should Left State Councilor Park Gyewon be at the top?
هل يجب أن يكون عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر بارك جيون في القمة؟
Should he?
يجب عليه؟
Left State Councilor Park Gyewon…
عضو مجلس الدولة اليساري بارك جيون ...
There is a carver at Beobrae Temple.
يوجد نحات في معبد بيوبراي.
-Did you find him? -Yes.
-هل وجدته؟  -نعم.
He recently made an object for a monk named Hyekang upon request
لقد صنع مؤخرًا شيئًا لراهب اسمه Hyekang عند الطلب
and it is as you expected.
وهو كما توقعت.
Ready my horse.
جاهز حصاني.
There is someplace I must be.
هناك مكان يجب أن أكون فيه.
Yes, my lord.
نعم سيدي.
Amusing, is it not?
مسلية ، أليس كذلك؟
The fate of the nobles who have always looked down on us
مصير النبلاء الذين لطالما نظروا إلينا بازدراء
lies in my very hands.
تقع في يدي.
KILL LIST
قتل القائمة
I request an audience with His Majesty.
أطلب مقابلة جلالة الملك.
How could you expect to speak with His Majesty
كيف تتوقع أن تتحدث مع جلالة الملك
when he remains unconscious?
عندما يظل فاقدًا للوعي؟
The royal physician has prohibited anyone from entering,
منع الطبيب الملكي أي شخص من الدخول ،
so please leave.
لذا يرجى المغادرة.
It was you who raised the monk, was it not?
كنت أنت من ربى الراهب أليس كذلك؟
Inform my King…
أبلغ الملك ...
that I wish to speak with him
أن أتحدث معه
in private.
بخصوصية.
-He knows about Siwol? -Yes, Your Majesty.
-يعرف عن Siwol؟  -نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
The former King was a feeble monarch and leader.
كان الملك السابق ملكًا وقائدًا ضعيفًا.
He was kind and righteous, but indecisive.
كان طيبًا وصالحًا ، لكنه كان مترددًا.
He was merciful, but was never authoritative.
كان رحيمًا ، لكنه لم يكن أبدًا موثوقًا به.
If there had been another member of the royal family who was more worthy,
إذا كان هناك فرد آخر في العائلة المالكة كان أكثر جدارة ،
I would not
وأود أن لا
have crowned him as king.
توجوه ملكا.
My father had been living happily with his books as friends.
كان والدي يعيش بسعادة مع كتبه كأصدقاء.
Those who forced him onto a throne he did not covet
أولئك الذين أجبروه على العرش لم يشتهيه
were the so-called meritorious subjects.
كانوا ما يسمى بالموضوعات الجديرة بالتقدير.
That is the fate of being born a royal
هذا هو مصير أن تكون ملكًا
and the price of benefiting from being one.
وثمن الاستفادة من أن تكون واحدًا.
However, the one who disregarded the weight of his duties
ومع ذلك ، فإن من استغنى عن ثقل واجباته
was your father.
كان والدك.
Is that why…
الهذا فعلت ذلك…
you pressured him that harshly?
ضغطت عليه بقسوة؟
It was to prevent him
كان لمنعه
from losing his way as a king.
من ضياع طريقه كملك.
Do you believe you have that right?
هل تعتقد أن لديك هذا الحق؟
My love for this country
حبي لهذا البلد
must have bestowed that power within me.
يجب أن تكون قد منحت تلك القوة بداخلي.
To mold both my father and me into benevolent kings
لتشكيل كل من والدي وأنا في الملوك الخيرين
is the reason you pressured us?
ما سبب ضغطك علينا؟
Your beliefs and what you deem ideal
معتقداتك وما تراه مثاليًا
are the reason
هي السبب
I did not believe in you.
لم اؤمن بك
It were the officials who pressured me in the name
كان المسؤولون هم من ضغطوا علي بالاسم
of filial duty.
من واجب الأبناء.
And by deceiving your mother, you have violated
وبخداع والدتك تكون قد انتهكت
the sacred oath.
القسم المقدس.
You have caused mayhem in the name of strengthening royal authority.
لقد أحدثت الفوضى باسم تقوية السلطة الملكية.
How are your actions…
كيف هي أفعالك ...
any different to those of the deposed King?
أي يختلف عن الملك المخلوع؟
The royal family
العائلة المالكة
was robbed of its authority by its subjects.
سُلبت سلطتها من قبل رعاياها.
Like you said,
مثلما قلت،
it is about time I regain the power vested in my blood.
لقد حان الوقت لاستعادة القوة المخولة في دمي.
Please put an end to this.
الرجاء وضع حد لهذا.
It is already too late.
لقد فات الأوان بالفعل.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Please return to the palace.
ارجوك ارجع للقصر
It is still not too late.
فإنه لا يزال لم يفت بعد.
Your Majesty, an urgent message was sent from the palace.
جلالة الملك ، تم إرسال رسالة عاجلة من القصر.
Tonight, an unfortunate incident will take place.
الليلة ، سيحدث حادث مؤسف.
An unfortunate incident?
حادثة مؤسفة؟
What about Consort Park?
ماذا عن كونسورت بارك؟
What happened to her?
ماذا حدث لها؟
Where is the consort?
أين الرفيق؟
I am here to discard the body of a deceased court maid.
أنا هنا للتخلص من جثة خادمة محكمة متوفاة.
She is from the Queen Dowager's palace.
هي من قصر الملكة الأرملة.
I was told to discard the ghastly body immediately.
قيل لي أن أتخلص من الجثة المروعة على الفور.
Wait. Don't look.
انتظر.  لا تنظر.
She was tortured by the Office of Palace Eunuchs.
تعرضت للتعذيب من قبل مكتب الخصيان في القصر.
Those despicable rats.
تلك الفئران الحقيرة.
Leave with it immediately!
اتركيه على الفور!
There she is!
ها هي ذا!
Please tell me
أرجوك قل لي
this is not a dream.
هذا ليس حلم.
It is not.
ليس.
You are awake.
انت مستيقظ.
Lord Park, Left Minister No came by to see you.
لورد بارك ، الوزير الأيسر لا أتى لرؤيتك.
Left Minister No came by at this late hour?
غادر الوزير لا جاء في هذه الساعة المتأخرة؟
Yes, my lord.
نعم سيدي.
He waited quite a while but then left for the palace.
انتظر قليلاً ثم غادر إلى القصر.
He requested that I forward this to you.
لقد طلب أن أحيل هذا إليكم.
Lord Park,
لورد بارك ،
I am headed to the palace as the Queen Dowager has summoned me.
توجهت إلى القصر حيث استدعتني الملكة الأرملة.
Although it is disloyal to ignore a royal command,
على الرغم من أنه من غير المخلص تجاهل أمر ملكي ،
for some reason, my feet wish to stay in place.
لسبب ما ، قدمي ترغب في البقاء في مكانها.
However, to know that you are someplace else
ومع ذلك ، لتعلم أنك في مكان آخر
puts me at ease.
يريحني.
KILL LIST
قتل القائمة
Father!
أب!
We have a serious situation.
لدينا وضع خطير.
Have the heads of traitors displayed outside the West Gate
اجعل رؤوس الخونة معروضة خارج البوابة الغربية
to warn the officials who come and go.
لتحذير المسؤولين الذين يأتون ويذهبون.
Your order… is my command.
طلبك ... هو أمري.
The stench of blood is everywhere.
رائحة الدم في كل مكان.
How sickening.
كيف مقزز.
I will have your chambers filled with flowers.
سوف امتلأ غرفك بالورود.
As if a few flowers
كما لو كان القليل من الزهور
are enough to cover the stench.
تكفي لتغطية الرائحة الكريهة.
TRAITOR KO MOONHYUNG TRAITOR HONG JINHWA
الخائن كو مونهيونغ الخائن هونغ جينهوا
TRAITOR NO KYUNGMOON
الخائن لا كيونغ مون
BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
Translated by Hye-lim Park
ترجمه هاي ليم بارك